# **Hui Zhang**

## Senior Software Engineer - SyllogisTeks

Ballwin, MO - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Hui-Zhang/387491612e30d846

High-performance and self-motivated professional with strong software development experience, particularly specialized in web-based solutions, cross-platform integration and Internet/Intranet software development.

Over 20 years of experience in the IT industry, focusing on innovation, success and achievement.

Platforms: Windows, Unix, Mac OS X, DOS

Middleware: EJB, MTS, COM

Application Server: Websphere, Weblogic, Jrun, .NET

Languages: Java, node.js, scala, XML, XSLT, Xquery, JavaScript, HTML, Shell Scripting (csh/ksh), PL/SQL

Database: Oracle 10g/11g, postgresql, Sybase, MS SQL Server Networking: REST, SOAP, web service, RPC, Socket programming

IDE: Eclipse, WSAD, intelliJ Visual Café
Testing Tools: Xrunner, Jtest, Junit, XMLUnit

Other Tools: OSM (Oracle order management), ASAP, UIM, Concept Wave Order Care, Microsoft Commerce

Server 2000, Rational Rose, Visio, Toad Design Patterns: MVC, Java design patterns

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

SyllogisTeks - March 2016 to Present

Java, node.js, scala, REST API, AWS, cloud foundry, kafka, agile, intelliJ, postgresql

SyllogisTeks - March 2016 to Present

Maintenance development in Java, scala for TSM and TSM pipeline advancement application for trait stacking management, 100% agile development.

Developed new REST API application called plant-passport which is the central piece to enable tracking at plant level, in node.js on postgresql database, deployed through cloud foundry to AWS cloud, 100% agile development.

SyllogisTeks - January 2004 to Present

Design and develop software "LEADS", a capital project targeted to increase the value of Monsanto's Biotechnology portfolio by enabling more rapid development of higher quality trait projects, my focus area is ADR (analyzed data repository), we are merging trait related statistically analyzed data from various data repositories and projects in Monsanto to one integrated repository with very large data set, and providing high through-put application as tool to support data mining and gene advancement decision making. (Jan. 2004 - Present)

Design and develop software "PDAT" to support data mining for biotech researchers and statisticians to find new genes which will result in positive phenotype for crops. (Sept. 2003 - Dec. 2003)

# **Lead Engineer for Order Manager**

Charter Communication - February 2008 to February 2016

OM. CBOM) project

Java design patterns, OSM, XQuery, Java, JavaScript, Concept Wave Order Care, Oracle 10g/11g, test first, web service, JMS, SOAP, GIT, Hibernate, Spring, Maven

Lead engineer in design, development and application support of OM, CBOM. OM/CBOM are among the most mission critical software applications in Charter which automates provisioning, directory listing, TPVU processing and etc., also it provides task management for automation fallouts. As lead engineer, I successfully and smoothly took over the development and production support of outsourced project "OM" and "CBOM" in a shockingly short time frame. Before the takeover, it faced putting-off-fire emergency mode after each production deployment, after take over, for development I was in charge of, it became virtually defect free immediately (meaning no new defect introduced), kept the record till now (8 years already).

Brought object oriented design and object oriented development to procedure based OM/CBOM, created home grown unit testing framework to OM/CBOM, brought in test first methodology, brought in design patterns to OM/CBOM application development to solve complicated design/development problems in object oriented way, make it more readable, easier to maintain and less error prone.

OSM certified developer, working on nextGen project which is on Oracle OSM platform.

#### Senior Business Consultant

Sykes - September 2003 to February 2008

MVC and Java design patterns, Rational Rose, tomcat, Oracle 8I, Jsp, Servlet, Struts), Junit, XMLUnit, XML, XSL/XSLT, JavaScript, POS (Point of Service, Web Service is one kind of implementation of POS), Swing, swixml

Methodology used: TestFirst and XP

Sykes - September 2003 to February 2008

#### Architect/Senior Software Engineer

SSE Inc - March 2001 to September 2003

Responsibilities differ from project to project)

MVC and Java design patterns, Rational Rose, Visio, WSAD, Toad, Websphere, Oracle 8I, J2EE (EJB, Servlet), LDAP, Jtest, PL/SQL

Methodology used: RUP

#### Responsible as architect, mentor and Java developer

SSE Inc - December 2001 to August 2003

for the large mission critical warehouse system rewrite project. Spearhead engineering of creative solutions for critical system components, contributed to both software and data analysis and design, actively involved in coding and mentoring in development phase

Member of Security Vendor selection project, represented WMS group to define security requirement, and helped to evaluate and select security vendor.

Jrun, EJB, SOAP, XML, XSLT, Servlet, JSP, Visual Cafe Architect in the framework development.

Design and develop a generic framework for software development in J2EE environment.

Benefits for using this framework:

- Ease coding effort, largely cut development time
- Standardize coding
- Less steep learning curve for developers not much experienced with J2EE
- Less error prone
- Force separation of presentation tier from business and data tiers because of use of XML

Microsoft Commerce Server 2000, IIS5.0, COM+, MSMQ, SQL Server 2000, VB6.0, ASP, DHTML One of two lead developers.

Client site: LCMS

- Developed an Internet order taking site (cphMall shop.cph.org) for LCMS using CS2000 (Microsoft Commerce Server 2000), customized proprietary pipeline components.
- Developed an Intranet admin site for cphMall through bizdesk of CS2000

#### **Lead Engineer**

Ungerboeck Systems, Inc - April 1999 to December 2000

Internet development (Event Management)

Java, JSP, Servlet, EJB, Java Script, Weblogic, XML, XSLT, VB6.0, , ASP, Visual InterDev 6.0, COM, MTS, n-tie. Oracle8i

IEBMS is the Internet version of an enterprise-wide software for event based management system, targeted to the events, meeting and entertainment industries.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Architect in Internet development, responsible for laying out project and development architecture and framework.
- Lead Engineer in development.
- Defined system requirement of the IEBMS runtime environment, guiding pilot customers to design and configure their firewall for IEBMS runtime.

Product features and modules:

- Multilingual ready and highly customizable, n-tier architecture
- Calendar of Events (ASP and COM)
- Event Booking (ASP and COM)
- Venue Search, Specification and Availability (ASP and COM)
- Event Registration (EJB, JSP, Servlet, ASP and COM)

#### Consultant

Interim Technology - March 1998 to March 1999

HTML, DHTML, Java Script, Perl, CGI, SSL, Dreamweaver, NT4.0, Sun Solaris

Client site: Southwestern Bell

Implemented the enhancement of an Intranet map engine and fiber view tool. The Intranet application provides a web based map tool (similar to mapquest) for sells person to show customer the geographic layout of fiber or other communication features, and design new fiber connections with customers through the web tool.

LAN, WAN, NT4.0, RAS, IIS, FrontPage, JavaScript, Visual C++, ISAPI, VB, NT

Client site: Forever Corp

- In charge of web server and network administration of the IS department
- Designed and developed web pages for the company website.

- Designed and developed the multimedia web application (KIOSK) mainly using ISAPI technology in Visual C++
- Designed and developed a data management project using Visual Basic, Access database

#### **Software Engineer**

Vitek bioMerieux - January 1996 to March 1998

Visual C++, ActiveX, ASP, DHTML and ODBC, CORBA

Design and Prototype

- Project migration from AIX platform to Web Applications in windows NT using ActiveX, CGI, ASP and DHTML
- Analyzed the pros and cons for the company of using CORBA as the next generation technology, and presented to the IT department.

C, Motif, Xrunner, Perl, Unix

Y2k project

In charge of the evaluation, time estimation, scheduling, building, and development of the Y2K migration project. Coordinate with SQA for regressive testing utilizing Xrunner.

C, Motif, TCP/IP, Unix

Enhancement Release of LSN product

- Added functionality to generate reports in spread sheet compatible format, designed and developed an GUI interface to export reports to dos floppy from a Unix software
- Converted GUI applications from English version to international multilingual version.
- ISO documentation liaison of the IT department.

C++/C, Xwindow, TCP/IP dBaseIV, LANtastic

#### **Research Assistant**

SIUE - September 1993 to December 1995

Developed X Windows Tutoring Software, a visualization tool for a multi-routing network, simultaneous multiuser talk application, software to implement algorithms solving several variants for a graph knapsack problem.. Implemented various algorithms for a virtual circuit packet distribution network simulation.

Developed PC based database applications using dBaseIV for Central Housing Office and maintenance office at SIUE. Local Area Network (LANtastic) administration

C++, Fortran

# **Programmer/Analyst**

Jinsha Electric Institute - June 1992 to July 1993

Developed a control system software

### Software Engineer

FoxBASE - August 1991 to June 1992

Developed accounting software in FoxBASE, a GUI interface tool in FoxBASE, so programmers can design a user interface or report by drawing on the screen, and the code in FoxBASE for the user interface and report will be automatically generated at the end.

# **EDUCATION**

# **B.S in Applied Physics**

Chongqing Univ July 1991